okay all right well thank you all for
好吧好吧谢谢大家
coming
未来
my name is will Lyons with Oracle and
我的名字叫里昂（Lyons）和甲骨文（Oracle）
I'm joined on our panel discussion with
我参加了与我们的小组讨论
by Mike Milankovitch from the Eclipse
来自Eclipse的Mike Milankovitch
Foundation
基础
David Blevins from Tommy tribe at the
Tommy部落的David Blevins在
end marks little to my left from Ian
终点在Ian的左边几乎没有
Robinson from IBM and we're the session
来自IBM的Robinson，我们来参加
was originally entitled opening up Java
最初被称为开放Java
EE we've renamed it Eclipse Enterprise
EE我们已将其重命名为Eclipse Enterprise
for Java which is what we will be
对于Java，我们将成为
talking about I'm the moderator I'm
谈论我是主持人
gonna give a brief summary of this
对此做一个简短的总结
project and then I'll pass it over to my
项目，然后将其传递给我
colleagues and then we'll take questions
同事，然后我们会提问
in August
在八月
Oracle blogged about its intention to
甲骨文在博客中表示其意图
evaluate moving Java EE technologies to
评估将Java EE技术迁移到
an open source foundation we approached
我们接触过的开源基金会
IBM in Red Hat on this and they
IBM在Red Hat上和他们
indicated their support of this
表示他们对此的支持
initiative we evaluated a number of
我们评估了许多
foundations and selected the Eclipse
基础并选择了Eclipse
Foundation to host this project and we
基金会主持这个项目，我们
have recently taken the first step to
最近迈出了第一步
actually create an eclipse project which
实际上创建一个蚀项目
will be which will receive all of
将会收到所有
Oracle's Java EE 8 sources to form the
Oracle的Java EE 8来源构成了
nucleus of a new project that the
一个新项目的核心
Eclipse Foundation called Eclipse
Eclipse Foundation称为Eclipse
Enterprise for Java Eclipse Enterprise
Java Eclipse企业版Enterprise
for Java is a project that will be
Java是一个将
created at the Eclipse Foundation oracle
在Eclipse Foundation Oracle中创建
intends to contribute all of its Java EE
打算贡献其所有的Java EE
eight GlassFish sources to this project
该项目的八个GlassFish来源
together with other vendors like Red Hat
与其他供应商（如Red Hat）一起
and IBM and Tommy tribe we hope to
以及IBM和Tommy部落，我们希望
recruit community sponsorship for
招募社区赞助
technologies that are that exist within
存在于其中的技术
this project and we will also sponsor
这个项目，我们也将赞助
the technologies ourselves so this is an
技术本身，所以这是一个
open project which is intended to
开放项目，旨在
liver and a reference implementation
肝脏和参考实施
which is compatible with Java EE 8 and
与Java EE 8和
can serve as the basis for evolving Java
可以作为Java演进的基础
EE technologies in the future we have
未来的EE技术
created an open discussion forum which
创建了一个开放讨论论坛
you can join that's indicated on this
你可以加入这个
slide to discuss the project and offer
幻灯片讨论项目并提供
any feedback you have our intent in
您有我们的意图的任何反馈
creating the process or this project is
创建过程或该项目是
to create a project which is more nimble
创建一个更灵活的项目
than what you've seen from Java EE in
比您在Java EE中看到的
past years we've received a lot of
过去几年，我们收到了很多
feedback over the years that the
多年来的反馈
technology is not a evolving at a fast
技术不是飞速发展
enough pace to keep up with industry
足够跟上行业发展的步伐
changes we hope the EE forge a process
的变化，我们希望EE建立一个流程
will be more nimble we intend to make
我们打算使之更加敏捷
the project more flexible the software
项目更灵活的软件
will be available via an eclipse license
将可以通过日食许可证获得
so readily distributable we will
如此易于分配，我们将
open-source TC case so that they are
开源TC案例
available for testing your own
可用于测试自己的
implementations so it's much more
实现，因此还有更多
flexible from a licensing perspective
从许可角度看很灵活
and it's more open in that it's a
它更开放，因为它是
community driven process we intend the
社区驱动的过程，我们打算
current Java EE or JCP process Oracle is
Oracle当前的Java EE或JCP流程
the primary vendor it's the spec lead
主要供应商是规格负责人
for the overall specification at EE 4j
EE 4j的总体规格
we intend to create a more level playing
我们打算创造一个更具水平的比赛
field where Oracle is only one of
Oracle只是以下领域之一
multiple vendors and community sponsors
多个供应商和社区赞助商
of the project just some details on the
该项目的一些细节
project we intend to transition to the
我们打算过渡到的项目
EE 4j project early we hope next
EE 4j项目提早我们希望下一步
calendar year by early next year we're
到明年年初的日历年
starting immediately GlassFish 5r Java
立即开始GlassFish 5r Java
e8 reference implementations technology
e8参考实现技术
compatibility kits and product
兼容性套件和产品
documentation we intend to create a
我们打算创建的文档
process for evolving existing specs and
改进现有规格的过程，以及
creating new specifications and a
创建新的规范和
process for establishing compatible
建立兼容的过程
implementations
实作
we intend for the technology to evolve
我们打算技术发展
we hope that technologies like micro
我们希望像微型这样的技术
profile may be evaluated for inclusion
个人资料可能会被评估为包含
in this project and just a message to
在这个项目中，只是向
Oracle's current licensees we intend to
我们打算将Oracle当前的被许可人
support licensees or vendors producing
支持被许可人或供应商生产
compatible Java EE eight independent
兼容Java EE八独立
implementations so Java EE 8 will be
实现，因此Java EE 8将成为
supported for its full lifecycle Oracle
支持其整个生命周期Oracle
itself intends to deliver a Java EE 8
本身打算交付Java EE 8
implementation so we hope this will
实施，所以我们希望这会
provide a more nimble or more flexible
提供更灵活或更灵活的方式
more open process and we'll begin by
更开放的过程，我们将从
implementing a compatible reference
实施兼容的参考
implementation early next year and we've
明年年初实施，我们已经
got multiple vendors supporting the
有多家供应商支持
initiative and we hope to create or
主动，我们希望创造或
recruit community sponsors to create a
招募社区赞助商来创建
truly community driven platform so with
真正的社区驱动平台
that we've had a the Eclipse Foundation
我们有一个Eclipse基金会
we've created a top-level Charter
我们创建了一个顶级章程
document which is open for feedback at
可在以下位置获取反馈的文档
this point I'd like to turn it over to
这一点我想把它转到
Mike Milankovitch Mike maybe you want to
迈克·米兰科维奇迈克·也许你想
introduce yourself and tell us more
介绍自己，并告诉我们更多
about the project from your point of
关于您的观点
view
视图
thanks well yeah so for those who don't
很好，是的，所以对于那些不这样做的人
know me I'm Mike Milankovitch I'm the
知道我，我是Mike Milankovitch，我是
executive director of the Eclipse
Eclipse执行董事
Foundation the coop sound ation has been
合作社声音的基础是
around now for 13 and a half years and
现在大约十三年半了
we've been I think a mainstay in the
我们一直是我认为
Java ecosystem and obviously we're
Java生态系统，显然我们
thrilled to welcome GlassFish in the
激动地欢迎GlassFish加入
Java EE code base into the Eclipse
Eclipse中的Java EE代码库
community and looking forward to
社区，期待着
welcoming many of you to as active
欢迎你们中的许多人活跃起来
participants in in the Eclipse community
Eclipse社区的参与者
as well so welcome and looking forward
也欢迎和期待
to working with all of you so the draft
与大家一起工作，所以草稿
document that's up there is a top-level
上面的文档是顶层的
project charter and I don't think it's
项目章程，我不认为这是
appropriate for us to go into sort of a
适合我们进入
lesson on how projects work at the
关于项目如何在
Eclipse Foundation but suffice it to say
Eclipse Foundation，但足以满足要求
this is sort of the top-level governing
这是顶级治理
document for how the open source project
文档如何进行开源项目
is going to be run
将要运行
and so things there's if you drill down
因此，如果您向下钻取，就会有事情发生
into it there's things like you know how
就像你知道如何
do committers get elected and those
提交者是否当选，那些
kinds of governance topics that some
一些治理主题
people love to dive into and many people
人们喜欢潜入，很多人
just gloss over and use it as a good way
只是掩饰并作为一种好方法
to make sure they fall asleep at night
确保他们晚上入睡
when they're lying in bed I think the
当他们躺在床上时，我认为
important thing about this document is
关于此文件的重要之处是
that it represents a stepping stone to
它代表了
making this a truly community lead
使之成为真正的社区领导
vendor-neutral exercise for innovating
与供应商无关的创新练习
in the enterprise Java space I think
我认为在企业Java领域
that's really what we're all trying to
这就是我们所有人都在尝试的
get to here
到这里
nimble is a great way to describe it but
敏捷是描述它的好方法，但是
it is also important to recognize that
同样重要的是要认识到
this document is really only talking
这个文件真的只是在说
about the process by which we're going
关于我们要进行的过程
to be managing the code the source code
管理代码的源代码
and so it's going to be about the the
所以这将是关于
source code and the tcks
源代码和tcks
that are coming over as open source to
成为开源的
eclipse anybody who's been following me
让一直跟随我的人黯然失色
on Twitter or on my blog note that I've
在Twitter或我的博客上，请注意我已经
said that the process of doing how we're
说我们做事的过程
going to be doing specs going forward is
即将做的规格是
something that we're probably not even
我们可能甚至没有的东西
going to start talking about for two or
要开始谈论两个或
three months perhaps even longer and
三个月甚至更长
just so people understand why that's
只是人们知道为什么
true is we at Eclipse firmly believe
的确，我们在Eclipse坚信
that well to coin a phrase code talks
很好地表达短语代码对话
and walks
和废话散步
right I mean this is an open source
对，我的意思是这是一个开源
project and the faster we can get this
项目，我们可以更快地得到它
thing boot strapped so that it is
东西的靴子绑好了
functioning as an open source project
充当开源项目
the fast the more the quicker we can get
速度越快，我们就能越快
back to actually talking about
回到实际谈论
innovation in Java and we want to help
Java创新，我们希望为您提供帮助
this community get to that stage as
这个社区达到了这个阶段
absolutely as quickly as we want as we
绝对快如我们所愿
possibly can just one point of
可能只有一点
clarification when Mike said he
澄清迈克说废话他
wasn't actually specifically referring
实际上不是专门指
to the specifications so no
到规格所以没有
yeah sorry that's that's not at all what
是的，对不起，那根本不是
I meant what I meant is the faster we
我的意思是我的意思是我们更快
can get - the faster we can get this
可以得到-我们可以更快地得到这个
team back to coding the faster we can
团队尽快恢复编码
actually start to demonstrate results to
实际开始证明结果
the community and I think that's
社区，我认为那是
ultimately what everybody wants to see
最终每个人都想看到的
is they want us we are all here are
他们想要我们吗，我们都在这里
going to be judged ultimately by the
最终将由
progress we show on making Java better
我们在改善Java方面所取得的进步
right ultimately that's what everybody
最终，这就是每个人
is a developer wants to see is they want
是开发者想要看到的，是他们想要的
to see this platform moving forward in a
看到这个平台向前发展
way that helps them do their job better
帮助他们更好地完成工作的方式
and I think so that's what we're trying
我想这就是我们正在尝试的
to get get to as quickly as we can and
尽可能快地到达
then the second thing is I don't think
那第二件事是我不认为
it's really been enough attention has
真的足够多的关注了
been given to the fact that Oracle is
甲骨文是
going to be open sourcing the T CK's
将公开采购T CK
right so for many for the in the entire
对很多人来说都是这样
history of Java EE the T CK's have been
Java EE的历史
a very a control point a way that Oracle
一个非常重要的控制点，Oracle
has exercised control over this
已经对此进行了控制
ecosystem and by making those open
生态系统并使它们开放
source I think that that's actually
消息来源，我认为那实际上是
that's actually a very fundamental
这实际上是非常基本的
change to the dynamics of this ecosystem
改变这个生态系统的动态
and the fact that people are going to be
人们将成为
for the first time able to download and
首次能够下载和
run the tcks and see if their
运行the，看看他们是否
implementations are compliant is going
实现是合规的
to hopefully bring other players to this
希望将其他玩家带到这里
to this table is be able to build
到此表就可以建立
implementations without the sort of
没有那种实现
pay-to-play kind of model that we had
我们拥有的付费游戏模型
before so those those two things getting
之前那两件事
the open source projects in the source
源代码中的开源项目
code going as fast as we can I want to
代码以我们想要的最快速度运行
be able to see people downloading
能够看到有人下载
running code from eclipse.org websites
从eclipse.org网站运行代码
as soon as possible getting the tcks
尽快得到the头
over as quickly as possible those two
尽快越过那两个
things are are what's going to be our
事情就是我们要做的
focus for the next little while
接下来的一小会儿
at some point in parallel we'll start
在平行的某个时刻，我们将开始
talking about what is the specification
谈论什么规格
process going to look like but we're a
过程看起来像，但我们是
little ways away from that so I guess my
一点点距离，所以我猜我
message to you is we are going to be
给您的讯息是我们将成为
going as hard as we can to make this an
尽我们所能
open-source a successful open source
开源成功的开源
project
项目
and this is a very large undertaking and
这是一项非常大的事业，
I thank you in advance for your trust
我预先感谢您的信任
and patience as we move this forward and
和耐心，我们向前迈进，
with that I'll turn it over to David am
这样我就交给大卫
I supposed to say what not to Ramona the
我应该对拉莫那说什么
question I forgot you might might want
问题我忘了你可能想要
to comment on the project sure effective
对项目发表意见，肯定有效
on it I guess that I would say that this
关于它，我想我会说
is a long time coming obviously right
很长一段时间来显然是正确的
and I think that I could have a couple
我想我可以有几个
net perspectives on our ecosystem and
对我们生态系统的净观点
the sense that I think that our IP model
我认为我们的IP模式
has slowed us down over the last several
在最近的几个时间里让我们放慢了脚步
years and this is going to be one of the
年，这将是其中之一
things that make us go quite a lot
使我们前进很多的事情
faster because it encourages
更快，因为它鼓励
contribution
贡献
quite honestly taking effectively
诚实地有效地采取
licensing away from the picture it does
从图片上许可
remove a barrier
消除障碍
I know we're all technical people's so
我知道我们都是技术人员
we like to think of the technical
我们喜欢考虑技术
reasons why we're slow but that is an
我们慢的原因，但这是一个
actual reason that we don't really think
我们没有真正思考的实际原因
about on a regular basis so this is
关于定期，所以这是
gonna be one of the things that kind of
会成为那种事情之一
make us go a lot faster than we've gone
使我们前进的速度比过去快得多
before we've seen in micro profile for
在我们的微观资料中看到之前
example with all of us together payara
我们所有人在一起的榜样
and everybody here that we've picked up
我们这里的每个人
pace very very quickly
节奏非常快
I think that's shown kind of an example
我认为这是一个例子
of what our future can look like there's
我们的未来看起来像
been controversy over the name I guess I
我猜我对这个名字一直有争议
have strong feelings that I like the
有强烈的感觉，我喜欢
name Java but I also don't care too much
命名Java，但我也不太在乎
about the name of the band at this
关于这个乐队的名字
moment I really just care about the
那一刻我真的只在乎
music and so I want to see what kind of
音乐，所以我想看看
music we're gonna play and I think we
我们要播放的音乐，我想我们
probably could play some pretty awesome
可能会发挥一些很棒
music when we get to that part and I'm
音乐，当我们到达那部分，而我
really looking forward to it to be
真的很期待它
honest the access to the T CK's is one
老实说，使用T CK的方法之一
of the biggest wins of this entire thing
这件事最大的胜利
you know even even us you know a little
你甚至连我们都知道
Tommy tribe has had a hard time getting
汤米部落很难
access to the T CK's
访问T CK
and not because everyone's ill-will it's
而不是因为每个人都有病，这是
just the way this the game set up but it
只是游戏设置的方式，但是
can be difficult you know Apache was
知道Apache可能很难
responsible for getting us a TCK they
他们负责给我们一个TCK
eventually decided to stop signing the
最终决定停止签署
agreement so there's no change in Oracle
协议，因此Oracle没有任何变化
side of the fence but Apache changed
栅栏的一面，但是Apache变了
their heart and then suddenly no TCK for
他们的心，然后突然没有TCK
tummy and that was one of the reasons
肚子，那是原因之一
why it took a really long time for each
为什么每个人都花很长时间
seven to happen in Tommy not technical
汤米发生的七件事与技术无关
reasons again again just just the
再次的原因只是
logistics of the way we've been playing
我们一直玩的方式的后勤
the game those barriers aren't going
在游戏中那些障碍并没有消除
away
远
so not only we're going to see things of
所以我们不仅会看到
the existing players adopt stuff faster
现有的玩家更快地采用东西
but we're gonna see new players and I
但我们会看到新的球员和我
think that that's one of the best things
认为那是最好的事情之一
about this whole thing seeing another
关于这整个事情看到另一个
generation of EE implementations
EE实现的生成
regardless of what the e's stand for I
不管e代表我什么
don't think it matters I'm gonna call it
没关系，我要称呼它
EE forever I never really elongated it
永远的EE我从未真正拉长它
in the first place I never really said
首先，我从未真正说过
Enterprise Edition I don't have the time
企业版我没有时间
or patience I guess so I'm really really
还是耐心，我想我真的
excited to see the new people that come
很高兴看到新来的人
into the market you know that is one of
进入市场，你知道这是其中之一
the things that we really need we have
我们真正需要的东西
you know kind of the young vendors
你知道那种年轻的商人
amongst us ourselves and payara but I
在我们自己和payara之间，但我
think we're gonna see a bunch more and
认为我们会看到更多
that's how you know when this thing is
那就是你怎么知道这件事是什么时候
gonna go much better for the next 10
接下来的10年会更好
years is when there's two three more
岁月是还有两个三
that show up and they may be run by just
出现，它们可能只是由
one person at the time but you know
当时只有一个人，但你知道
Tommy was one person at a time and now
汤米一次又一次是一个人
we're a company so you know I I'm very
我们是一家公司，所以你知道我非常
positive optimistic about the next
积极乐观的下一个
several years
几年
there are definitely going to be
肯定会有
challenges but there's no gain if there
挑战，但没有收获
aren't challenges and so you know I have
不是挑战，所以你知道我有
things that I would like to see taken
我想看的东西
care of things that I would hope to see
照顾我希望看到的东西
in the way we define specifications or
以我们定义规格的方式或
enforce them but at this moment I'm very
强制执行，但此刻我非常
very optimistic about what we can do I
对我们能做什么我非常乐观
see far more advantages and
看到更多的优势，
disadvantages awesome Ark Orion would
Ark Orion的缺点
you like to make some comments yeah I
你想发表一些意见，是的，我
mean I echo pretty much what David has
意思是我几乎回应了大卫的一切
been saying companies individuals and
一直在说公司个人
various groups have been asking for this
各个团体一直在要求这个
for a long long time asking for Java to
很长一段时间要求Java
be moved to an open standard process or
移至开放标准流程或
to an open source foundation so to
到开源基金会，以便
actually have that happen now I think I
其实现在发生了
was talking to these guys earlier this
在这之前跟这些家伙说话
time last year didn't think this was
去年的时间不认为这是
gonna happen this was not something that
会发生，这不是那个
we actually thought was a realistic
我们实际上以为是现实的
possibility because we've been asking
可能性，因为我们一直在问
for it in the JCP for instance for a
例如在JCP中
long long time and Oracle hadn't budged
很久很久了，Oracle并没有让步
an inch so then have it happen is a
一英寸，然后发生它是
great thing it's it's a it's a victory
伟大的事情是胜利
for a lot of a lot of people groups and
很多人团体
vendors like I said but it's also a good
像我所说的供应商，但这也很好
thing for Oracle I you know said it on
Oracle的事情我知道
record before but I I'll say it again
录制之前，我再说一遍
you know I'd like to congratulate them
你知道我要祝贺他们
for having made that step because it
之所以采取这一步骤是因为
probably is the biggest thing to happen
可能是最大的事情
to the extended java ecosystem since
自从扩展到Java生态系统以来
open JDK and it's you know it's a big
打开JDK，您知道它很大
announcement at JavaOne it's probably
在JavaOne上宣布
not necessarily getting the level of
不一定获得
publicity I think it deserves but you
宣传我认为值得，但你
know we'll we'll wait and see in terms
知道我们会等着看的
of going forward I think that's you know
前进，我想那是你知道的
Java EE or e4j or EE or whatever it is
Java EE或e4j或EE或任何它
that you want to call it
你想称呼它
for the next generation coming down
为了下一代
whatever it is that you want to call it
无论你想称呼它是什么
has got a great future as long as
只要有一个美好的未来
everybody who is interested in it in the
每个对它感兴趣的人
past and in the present is willing to
过去和现在愿意
commit to it for the future we often
致力于未来，我们经常
forget or some segments of the industry
忘记或行业的某些领域
often forget that you know there are
经常忘记你知道有
there are a number of Java EE compliant
有许多符合Java EE的规范
application servers out there they've
他们在那里的应用服务器
been around for a number of years
已经存在了很多年
they're deployed very very widely it's
他们被非常广泛地部署
extremely successful as a technology and
作为一项技术非常成功，
then there are other Java technologies
然后还有其他Java技术
that leverage those components within
利用其中的这些组件
Java EE or the application servers
Java EE或应用程序服务器
themselves without necessarily always
自己不一定总是
paying the right level of due
支付适当的到期费用
acknowledgment I think to the underlying
我认为对底层的认可
technologies so everybody in some way I
技术，所以每个人都以某种方式
think is dependent upon Java itself or
认为取决于Java本身或
in its individual components so that's
在其各个组成部分中
why I like I said at the keynote I think
为什么我喜欢我在主题演讲中说的
everybody should get together behind
每个人都应该聚在一起
this and really push it forward because
并真正推动它前进，因为
it's gonna succeed or fail not because
它会成功或失败不是因为
Oracle has open sourced it but because
Oracle已将其开源，但是因为
Oracle IBM Red Hat Tommie tribe payara
Oracle IBM Red Hat Tommie部落Payara
and everybody in this room and beyond
还有这个房间里的所有人
get involved because if you don't that
参与进来，因为如果你不这样做
is a little it's just gonna fail
有点失败
so Mike asked me over a beer yesterday
所以迈克昨天问我喝啤酒
well woody what's your criteria for
伍迪，你的标准是什么
success for this project so what I think
这个项目的成功，所以我认为
is is that this time next year at
是明年的这个时候
JavaOne we're still talking about the
JavaOne我们仍在谈论
enterprise Java platform we're talking
我们正在谈论的企业Java平台
about what is done in eclipse and we're
关于日食的事情，我们
talking about how bits of it are owned
谈论它的部分是如何拥有的
by a much broader set of people when
由更广泛的人群
when we were going through this sort of
当我们经历这种
the the early discovery process of what
什么的早期发现过程
it might mean for IBM who I work for
对于我工作的IBM可能意味着
you know I what I got the things I
你知道我得到的东西
wanted I wanted greater ownership of the
想要我想要更大的所有权
technology
技术
is amongst a wider distribution of
属于更广泛的
people paths which will be us so it's
人的路径，这将是我们，所以
like you know we can do more here we can
就像你知道我们可以在这里做得更多
own more of the specifications in order
拥有更多规格
to have more influence over you know the
对你有更大的影响力
details of how these things evolve and
这些事物如何演变的细节，以及
you know but we've got to do our bit
你知道，但我们必须尽力而为
we've got a we we've got to put our
我们有一个我们我们必须把我们的
hands up
举手
for some of these specifications some of
对于这些规范中的一些
these technologies - at which point my
这些技术-在那时
executive team went oh crap that's going
执行团队走了
to cost something which of course it
花费什么当然
will but you know what we want to be
会，但是你知道我们想要成为什么
able to do here is to take
能够在这里做的就是
responsibility for some of those things
对其中某些事情负责
but to get other people people that are
但是为了得到其他人
interested in the individual
对个人感兴趣
technologies putting their hands up -
技术举手-
and spreading the love around a bit so
并传播爱的周围
thank you all and at this point I think
谢谢大家，在这一点上，我认为
we'll open it up for questions we had a
我们将开放它来解决我们遇到的问题
debate earlier about whether we needed
早些时候辩论我们是否需要
to seat ourselves with the questions so
让我们自己解决问题
we like to encourage you to ask some
我们想鼓励您问一些
questions that you may have yes
您可能有的问题
rethread once again
再次重新穿线
but the one thing that actually jumped
但实际上跳了一件事
out to me is the term application server
对我来说，术语是应用程序服务器
learning
学习
I really wonder if that's gonna get
我真的很想知道那会不会
broken
破碎
as we know
据我们所知
sir always myself
先生总是我自己
because every ology
因为每一种学
I don't agree with that I'm open to the
我不同意我愿意接受
skin yeah actually I think that's a
皮肤是的，实际上我认为那是
perfect example of oh I'm sorry yeah the
完美的例子哦，对不起，是的
question is oh sure the solution the
问题是确定解决方案
question is the top level charter
问题是最高层次的宪章
includes reference to application server
包括对应用程序服务器的引用
I'll take responsibility for that just
我会为此负责
tests are used in the document
文档中使用了测试
application server as a tested meeting
应用服务器作为经过测试的会议
the question is could we eliminate that
问题是我们能否消除这一点
term from the top-level charter and in
顶级租船合同中的条款
effect to make it more use one time in
使其一次使用更多的效果
its place to represent a more flexible
它代表更灵活的位置
definition and I I think that's a very
定义，我认为这是一个非常
reasonable suggestion on everybody
对大家的合理建议
so I mean suggested on the list and I
所以我的意思是建议在名单上
think that that's a perfectly reasonable
认为那是完全合理的
edit to make and sure no problem
编辑以确保没有问题
let's make John Rock there we go there
让我们去John Rock那里去
we go I like this question from the
我们去，我喜欢这个问题
front next time so in Java EE 8 MVC was
下一次是在Java EE 8 MVC中
removed from the list with the new
从列表中删除新的
governance model could it be put back on
治理模型可以放回去
the list I mean I would say that once
清单我是说一次
the wants the project's up and running
希望项目启动并运行
it's down to the community where it goes
这取决于它去的社区
it really is not gonna be under the same
真的不会一样
kind of governance as it was in the past
过去的治理
if the community decides they want to
如果社区决定他们想要
put MVC back in why the hell would we
让MVC回到为什么我们会死的地方
say no to that well the only thing I
对那件事说不，我唯一的话
would add to that is I don't think we
会增加的是我不认为我们
would put dead code back in if there was
如果有的话，会把死代码放回去
a like a demonstrable functioning
像一个可演示的功能
project with people doing stuff then
然后与人一起做项目
yeah but that's you know that's the only
是的，但是那是你知道的，这是唯一的
caveat I would get on that so I would
请注意，我会继续这样做，所以我会
just say that MVC is currently the the
只是说MVC目前是
IP of Ivar Grimstad because it was
Ivar Grimstad的IP，因为它是
transferred from Oracle to him prior to
从甲骨文转移到他之前
all the opening movements and he's
所有的开头动作，他是
currently he has a panel this week a
目前他本周有一个小组
session this week and in the session he
在本周的会议中，他在会议中
intends to ask the audience what should
打算问观众应该怎么做
we do with it should we go and also put
我们应该去做，也要放
MVC into the Eclipse Foundation and so
MVC进入Eclipse Foundation等
if that's a topic that's near to your
如果那是您附近的话题
heart I would say definitely go to Ivar
我会说绝对要去伊瓦
Grimm's dad's session on this because he
格林在父亲的会议上，因为他
does intend to do whatever the world
打算做任何世界
wants despite the fact that he is
想要尽管他是
currently the sole despot owner he
目前他是唯一的仓库老板
doesn't really like that designation so
真的不喜欢那个名字，所以
you know he wants to do right by the
你知道他想做的正确
technology so if you have an opinion
技术，如果您有意见
definitely express it one more question
肯定再表达一个问题
what happens to the concept of profiles
配置文件的概念发生了什么
profile and full profile yet so to beat
个人资料和完整个人资料
it to be determined because that's part
要确定，因为那是一部分
of the spec process so we haven't got
规范流程，所以我们还没有
there yet I can just tell you that from
在那里，我只能告诉你
from my perspective one of the things
在我看来，其中一件事
that
那
so my sort of going in assumption or
所以我有点假设
whatever is that we've made it far too
不管我们做得如何
hard to create profiles in the past like
过去很难创建个人资料，例如
it was sort of a very big deal to be
这是一个很大的事情
able to create a profile and if you know
能够创建个人资料，如果您知道
if a if there's a group of community
如果有一个社区
people that want to pull together
想聚在一起的人
something that makes sense to them and
对他们有意义的东西
it's then I think we should be a lot
那时候我想我们应该很多
more open to those kinds of ideas and
对这些想法更开放
try to inspire more innovation there's a
尝试激发更多的创新
phrase I heard years ago that's really
我几年前听到的那句话是
stucked with with me that one of the
坚持与我，其中之一
things that open-source does is enable
开源所做的事情是启用
innovation through integration like a
通过整合创新
lot of what happens in open sources
开源中发生的很多事情
people putting together stuff that
人们把东西放在一起
hadn't been put together before in a
以前没有放在一起
particular way and I think that that's
特殊的方式，我认为那是
one path of innovation that we should
我们应该走的一条创新之路
definitely be trying to support I would
肯定会尝试支持我
just add as well I mean I was involved
只要加上，我的意思是我参与了
mmm along with some of these guys when
嗯，其中一些人
we were defining the full profile and
我们正在定义完整的个人资料，
the web profile you know the reason we
您知道我们的原因的网络配置文件
ended up with those with just those two
最后只有那两个
is cuz you know when you think about it
是因为您在考虑时知道
Java EE is done really well because of
Java EE的表现非常出色，因为
portability and the ability to if you
便携性和能力，如果您
really want to move move your
真的想搬家
application from one implementation to
从一个实现到
another if it says it's compliant so
另一个如果说它符合要求
profiles give you that surety that you
个人资料使您确信
know at least you know if you've
至少知道你是否知道
developed an app that works on the web
开发了可在网络上运行的应用
profile for WebSphere it'll run on the
WebSphere的配置文件，它将在
web profile for EAP so you know we want
EAP的网络配置文件，所以您知道我们想要
we might want to do something a little
我们可能想做点事
bit more flexible than profiles but we
比配置文件更灵活，但是我们
absolutely need to maintain the
绝对需要维护
compatibility and the portability and
兼容性和可移植性以及
the interoperability aspects yeah and I
我和我之间的互操作性方面
guess I would say as like someone who
我猜我会说像某人
has only a web profile implementation
只有一个网络配置文件实施
and not a compliant full profile when I
而不是我的合规个人资料
would be absolutely on board with
绝对会与
maintaining that initial implementation
维持最初的实施
yeah yeah supports both profile and then
是的，同时支持个人资料和
we'll take it from there
我们从那里拿走
firstly I'm gonna go out on a limb and
首先，我要四肢走动，
say that maybe the people who invented
说，也许是发明的人
the name micro profile I don't know why
微型个人资料的名称，我不知道为什么
we call them things like maybe they
我们称他们为类似他们的东西
really so on the topic of profiles we've
的确如此，我们在个人资料方面
seen some vendor
看到一些供应商
generate pretty much the runtime when
生成几乎运行时
you build your applications things like
您构建应用程序之类的东西
wild fly and open Liberty and I think
苍蝇和开放自由，我认为
Pierre has something in the words like
皮埃尔有这样的话
you only bundle the Java aaps are you
你只捆绑了Java aap
going to use not so I think it would be
将不使用，所以我认为这将是
a good idea suggestion to standardize
一个标准化的好主意建议
this so that it can be done on any
这样就可以在任何
application server or runtime or
应用服务器或运行时或
whatever you want to call it instead of
任何你想称呼它而不是
you know being features so that some app
你知道功能，所以一些应用程序
servers have like we have at the moment
服务器具有我们目前的功能
it's kind of what we're doing a micro
这是我们正在做的一种微
profile okay oh yes and no so I think I
个人资料好吧，哦，是的，不是，所以我想我
think having a Java EE always has had a
认为拥有Java EE总是有一个
modular way of defining different
定义不同的模块化方式
technologies but the way in which
技术，但其中的方式
wildfly or Liberty or PI R or anybody
野蝇或Liberty或PI R或任何人
else
其他
Tommy tribe this determines that that's
汤米部落这确定那是
how their runtime is going to provide a
他们的运行时将如何提供
means for an application to say I need
表示申请需要的方式
this this and this and this is how they
这个这个这个这个
all get packaged together okay I don't
都打包在一起好吧我不
know I wouldn't be keen to standardize
知道我不愿意标准化
down to it that's that's an
直到那是一个
implementation detail in my mind well
我心中很好的实现细节
let's see what the community wants yeah
让我们看看社区想要什么
yes going yeah I have an opinion about
是的，是的，我对
that kind of level of modular I'm super
那种水平的模块化我超级
a big fan of basically uber jars with
基本上是超级罐子的忠实粉丝
all the stuff in one binary that you
所有的东西都放在一个二进制文件中
ship I actually don't like modularity
船，我实际上不喜欢模块化
and Tommy was based on the opposite
而汤米则基于相反的观点
concept of modularity like all app
像所有应用程序一样的模块化概念
servers have typically been desktop and
服务器通常是台式机，
thinking I gotta be able to swap out the
以为我可以换掉
video card and a sound card and I need
显卡和声卡，我需要
to be able to upgrade my RAM and all
才能升级我的RAM和所有
this kind of stuff and that leads to a
这种东西，导致一个
certain amount of weight in my opinion
我认为一定重量
that the weight justifies the modularity
重量证明模块化
and people asked for the modularity
人们要求模块化
because there's weight there and so with
因为那里有重量，所以
Tommy we definitely went the opposite
汤米，我们绝对是相反的
direction deliberately and said let's
故意故意说，让我们
build a laptop and everything's wired
建立一台笔记本电脑，一切都已连线
directly together so if there was a
直接在一起，所以如果有一个
modular spec we probably wouldn't
模块化规范，我们可能不会
lamented but we were already like super
感叹，但我们已经像超级
small and tiny and the things that would
小而微小的东西
make us faster have nothing to do with
使我们更快与之无关
the other things in the api's to have to
api中的其他内容
do with the fact that there's a
与有一个事实
artificial barrier between the JVM and
JVM和
the apps that run them in JVM such that
在JVM中运行它们的应用程序
when we start up all of us we have to
当我们启动所有人时，我们必须
scan the entire class path which means
扫描整个类路径，这意味着
iterating over all the jars listing all
遍历所有列出所有罐子的罐子
the class files which is not a portable
不可移植的类文件
thing to do by the way and then we got
顺便说一句，然后我们得到了
to read them all in with like a SM look
以SM外观阅读所有内容
for an annotation find all of the
对于注释，请找到所有
needles in the haystack throw away the
大海捞针扔掉
hay and then boot the app server up and
干草，然后启动应用程序服务器并
that takes a long time and if we got rid
这需要很长时间，如果我们摆脱了
of that stuff this whole we would be
这些东西，我们整个
starting up in like you know 0.2 seconds
像你知道的那样启动0.2秒
and no one would care about any
没有人会在意
modularity at that moment like I can get
那时我可以得到模块化
you down to a point one five seconds
你下降到五分之一秒
they'd be like I don't care that means
他们会觉得我不在乎这意味着
they got more stuff to click on you're
他们有更多东西可以点击你
not saving me anytime find another
任何时候都不救我找到另一个
problem to solve and I have a more
要解决的问题，我还有更多
pragmatic reason why I wouldn't want to
我不想的务实理由
start to start this thing off by talking
开始通过谈论开始这件事
about modularity because the last thing
关于模块化，因为最后一件事
I want to do on the day one of
我想在第一天做
establishing a new community is reinvent
重新建立一个新社区
that jigsaw versus OSGi wars for two
拼图与OSGi的战争有两个
years like I mean like is that really
像我这样的岁月是真的
what we want to start do first as much
我们要开始做的首先
fun as that is so you can like you know
很有趣，所以你可以喜欢你知道
write stuff on blogs forever and ever
永远在博客上写东西
and ever it's just not probably the most
而且它可能不是最
constructive dessert it's a good job
建设性的甜点，这是一个好工作
that eclipse has got nothing to do those
蚀什么都没做
[Music]
[音乐]
[Laughter]
[笑声]
come on Mike out nothing nothing I'm
迈克，出来，没事，我没事
good so Mike I have a pragmatic question
好，麦克，我有一个务实的问题
for you you know for somebody that
对于你，你知道某人
that's in the JCB from the inside
从内部在JCB中
the reality is running an organization
现实正在运行一个组织
that can support a set of technologies a
可以支持一套技术
large set of technologies like Java EE
像Java EE这样的大量技术
requires a lot of funding you know
你需要很多资金
there's a little bit of infrastructure
有一点基础设施
that goes into it the Sun process you
太阳进入你的过程
know and there's a TCK running the TCK
知道并且有一个运行TCK的TCK
itself there's evangelism and the like
本身就有传福音之类的
so what's your answer to that is this is
所以你对此的答案是
probably the largest undertaking that
可能是最大的任务
with all due respect it's probably one
带着所有应有的尊重，这可能是其中之一
of the largest undertaking that eclipse
蚀最大的事业
has has started
已经开始
what do you where do you expect the
你在哪里期望
funding to come from in order to
资金来自为了
effectively run this I just I thought
我以为我有效地运行了这个
will was writing a big jacket yeah it's
将要写一件大外套，是的
a personal bank account no that was
个人银行帐户
totally a joke make sure everybody
开个玩笑，确保所有人
totally a joke so that's a really good
完全是个笑话，那真的很好
question and you're absolutely right
问题，你是绝对正确的
this is a massive undertaking to do
这是一项艰巨的任务
right there's ultimately the Eclipse
最终有Eclipse
Foundation is a member supported
基金会受会员支持
organization and I think one of the
组织，我认为其中之一
things that we're gonna have to really
我们必须要做的事情
focus on over the next little while is
在接下来的一段时间内专注于
to make sure that this is sustainable so
确保这是可持续的
we're gonna have to go out there and
我们将不得不去那里，
recruit a whole bunch of new members and
招募一大堆新成员，
and you know look at other sources of
你知道看看其他来源
revenue as well but that's um you know
收入也一样，但是你知道
you're right there's no way that the
你是对的，没有办法
co-found a ssin has the resources at the
共同创建了一个拥有的资源
moment to do this without with zero
没有零的时刻
incremental revenue let's like the
增量收入就像
eclipse on Dacian is a not-for-profit
蚀达契安是非营利的
we've been managing this organization
我们一直在管理这个组织
for 13 and a half years where the goal
13年半的目标
is every year the number at the bottom
每年底部的数字是
is zero right so we're a lean
是零，所以我们是一个瘦子
organization it's not like we got like
组织，这不像我们
18 million dollars sitting in a bank
1800万美元坐在银行
account somewhere so we're gonna need
在某个地方记帐，所以我们需要
the support of the community and and one
社区的支持和
of the things that's so for the people
对人民来说是如此
that are in the room I mean people have
在房间里，我的意思是人们有
been talking about
一直在谈论
Java needs to be more free for a lot of
Java需要在许多方面更自由
years and your your companies are the
年，您的公司是
places where you work are companies that
您工作的地方是那些
are relying upon this platform and upon
依靠这个平台和
this ecosystem and so we're gonna be
这个生态系统，所以我们将成为
like knocking on doors looking for your
就像敲门寻找你的
support to make this a long-term
支持使其长期
sustainable solution for making job
可持续的就业解决方案
keeping Java free I would just add that
保持Java免费，我只想补充一点
I one of the statements that I made in
我发表的声明之一
the keynote which i think is valid is
我认为有效的主题演讲是
that by and large the majority the the
总的来说，
largest investment in EE has been on the
对EE的最大投资是
consumer side if you total up the number
消费方（如果您总计）
of hours that are all teams spend
所有团队花费的时间
rolling out upgrading learning
推出升级学习
developing writing EE it's so much
开发写作EE非常重要
larger than what the vendors put in by
比供应商投入的更大
comparison and opening up the tcks and
比较和开放技巧
things like that for everyone who has a
对于每个有一个
stake in EE to contribute even a little
持有EE股份以贡献一点
bit it does this whole movement does
一点，它完成了整个动作
open the doors to a very significant
打开一个非常重要的门
source of investment which is the world
世界的投资来源
that uses EE so if we understand our
使用EE，所以如果我们了解我们的
responsibility and we approach it
责任，我们来对待
accordingly we're all gonna have
因此，我们都会
something that lasts for a very very
持续很长一段时间的东西
long time
很久
and it's gonna have an even greater
而且会有更大的
amount of portability than we've ever
前所未有的便携性
seen it's been the kind of standard case
看到这是标准案例
where if you had an app that was
如果您有一个应用程序
supposed to work on three vendors a
应该在三个供应商上工作
bunch of the functionality will work on
一堆功能将在
all three but some of them will only
所有这三个，但其中一些只会
work on two and when the third one won't
在两个上工作，而第三个不会
work and your current status is that you
工作，您目前的状态是
just have to well either decide not to
只是必须要么决定不
use that third vendor or support it or
使用该第三方供应商或支持它，或者
not use that feature so you can stay on
不要使用该功能，因此您可以继续
all three and with the path going
所有这三者，以及前进的道路
forward what you would do is you'd go
转发你会做的就是你会去
straight to the TCK and the open source
直接进入TCK和开源
project that eclipse you would find the
蚀的项目，您会发现
test or where the test should be and you
测试或应该在哪里进行测试
would add it and then you would go knock
将其添加，然后您将敲门
on the third vendor and say hey you know
在第三个供应商上说，嘿，您知道
maybe you want to work that one out
也许你想一起工作
and you could do that openly in the
您可以在
public you wouldn't need a support
公开，您不需要支持
contract you would just say hey that's
合同你会说嘿
probably in your best interest to pass
可能符合您的最大利益
that test and this is an example of you
测试，这是你的一个例子
being in the driver's seat and making a
坐在驾驶员座位上
very small investment in portability
便携性投资很小
everybody's very small investments and
每个人的投资很小
portability can add up to mean a very
便携性加起来意味着非常
massive investment overall so I think we
总的来说，大量投资
need to understand that we are part of
需要了解我们是
this whole ecosystem and opening up of
整个生态系统和开放
these things is only magic if we
这些东西只有当我们
actually leverage it other questions
实际利用其他问题
I'll just make a comment on what's been
我只会评论发生了什么
discussed here I I work with Fujitsu is
这里讨论的与富士通的合作是
a major corporate entity and may we have
一个主要的公司实体，也许我们有
major applications that are based on the
基于的主要应用
EE and we have a lot of revenue that
EE，我们有很多收入
comes to us because of that but we're a
因此来到我们这里，但我们是
vendor who is not a member of eclipse at
不是eclipse成员的供应商
the present time and because of this
当前的时间，因此
move we are seriously considering
我们正在认真考虑的举动
becoming a member of Eclipse and I
成为Eclipse的一员，我
suspect that there are a lot of other
怀疑还有很多其他
vendors who are major who have major
有主要专业的供应商
products and and revenue that comes
产品和收益
because of the e product they're gonna
因为有了电子产品
be thinking the same way yeah we became
以同样的方式思考，是的，我们成为了
a member of the club's this last year
去年的俱乐部成员
after the creation of micro profile as
在创建微资料后
did payara and basically everybody who
做了payara，基本上每个人
had anything to do with that and yeah
与此有关，是的
well so it's you know that that's been
好吧，所以你知道那已经
part of the we've been a little small
我们的一部分已经很小
part your growth Mike yeah I think it's
是你成长的一部分Mike yeah，我想是
it's very very much appreciated maybe
也许非常感谢
it's more a comment than a question but
它不是问题而是评论，但
the I mean in companies people who are
我的意思是在公司里
deciding that such and such project and
决定某某项目以及
such team are going to use Java EE
这样的团队将使用Java EE
against other alternative around not
反对周围的其他选择
necessarily technical people not
不一定是技术人员
necessarily very we're aware of what the
一定非常我们知道
Eclipse Foundation is what open source
Eclipse Foundation是什么开源
is maybe well probably that I know at
也许我知道
least have a little idea on this topic
至少对这个话题有一点想法
and those people will rely more on
那些人会更多地依靠
communication and impressions they have
他们的沟通和印象
then on real facts on what's going on
然后根据实际情况
inside the Eclipse Foundation in the
在Eclipse Foundation中
transition the feeling I have so far is
转变我到目前为止的感觉是
that they are they are seeing a
他们是他们正在看到一个
situation that is in stable or I called
情况稳定或我打电话
used to be in charge not in charge
以前是负责人而不是负责人
anymore or I call worth supporting with
还是我呼吁值得支持
people and money and probably less
人和金钱，也许更少
supportive with people on money now so
现在支持有钱人
this is the this is the situation as a
这就是这种情况
situation of instability and if they do
不稳定的情况，如果这样做
not have a clear communication in the
没有清晰的沟通
upcoming month probably three six months
下个月大概三六个月
it's probably too much then they might
他们可能太多了
bail out from Java EE and deciding to
摆脱Java EE并决定
use other technologies to achieve the
使用其他技术来实现
same result in their application and
在他们的申请中同样的结果
those people may may be in charge of
那些人可能负责
teams of developer in the order of the
开发团队按顺序
thousands so it might be a period really
成千上万，所以这可能是一个时期
critical to get some clear communication
进行清晰沟通至关重要
to with them to see that to show them
跟他们一起看给他们看
that they are indeed people in charge
他们确实是负责人
even if the governance of the EE foj
即使EE foj的治理
stuff is not completely stable at least
东西至少不是完全稳定
that it is going to be stable in the
它将会在
next month or so and people and that
下个月左右，人们和那个
things are still going to to move
事情仍将继续
forward to innovation and thing like
前进到创新之类的东西
that so well do you have a communication
你的沟通很好
plan first of all we will can for those
首先要计划那些
customers who like to rely on the
喜欢依靠的客户
existing Java EE standard we at Oracle
Oracle现有的Java EE标准
we're supporting a Java EE 7
我们正在支持Java EE 7
implementation we just released Java EE
我们刚刚发布了Java EE的实现
8 through the Java community process
8通过Java社区过程
Oracle plans to deliver a Java EE eight
甲骨文计划交付Java EE 8
compliant commercial implementation
合规的商业实施
WebLogic server and that will be
WebLogic服务器，它将是
supported for many years so there is a
支持多年，所以有一个
long path forward for those customers
这些客户前进的路很长
but all that said I think your point is
但是我只说你的意思是
well-taken
精心挑选
we have been very open about this
我们对此非常开放
process we're trying to communicate
我们试图沟通的过程
openly and we do want to move quickly
公开地，我们确实想迅速行动
you know as Mike said earlier to get
你知道，正如迈克早先说过的
sources into the project to show that
来源进入项目以表明
it's real to recruit recruit community
招募社区是真实的
support for it so our hope is we can
支持它，所以我们的希望是我们可以
just move this project forward very
只是将这个项目向前推进
quickly just a comment on that we have a
很快就对我们有一个评论
milestone coming up
里程碑即将来临
on October 23rd we hope to ratify this
我们希望在10月23日批准
top-level charter that we've published
我们发布的顶级章程
here so if you have comments on that
如果您对此有意见
please get those comments in right away
请马上得到那些评论
we need to keep moving on this project
我们需要继续进行这个项目
once the Charter is ratified we can
《宪章》获得批准后，我们​​可以
begin to actually open real projects at
开始在以下位置实际打开真实项目
Eclipse into which we can contribute
我们可以贡献的Eclipse
source code to start making this project
开始制作这个项目的源代码
real so I just wanted to alert everybody
真实的，所以我只想提醒大家
that there's a milestone coming up on
有一个里程碑即将到来
October 23rd to finalize this document
10月23日定稿
and take the next step in implementing
并执行下一步
this project yet the only thing I'd add
这个项目，但我唯一要补充的是
to that is just in case anybody's
以防万一有人
wondering just because the by ratified
想知道只是因为批准
it means the cliff's Foundation Board of
这意味着悬崖的基础委员会
Directors is going to vote to approve it
董事将投票批准
to establish that new top-level project
建立那个新的顶级项目
that doesn't mean that we can't go back
这并不意味着我们不能回头
a month later or six months later or a
一个月后或六个月后或
year later to revise it we do consider
一年后修改它，我们考虑
these to be living documents and as the
这些是生活文件，并作为
circumstances change that we're you know
情况变了，我们知道
we're perfectly happy to have them to
我们非常高兴有他们参加
have them modified so it's not like it's
修改它们，这样就不一样了
whatever gets you know ratified on
无论您知道什么批准
October 23rd is the last and final say
10月23日是最后的发言权
forever and ever this is these are not
永远永远是这些不是
on stone tablets coming down from the
在从
mountain and the only other thing you
山和你唯一的另一件事
have sort of on the question what I'm
对我有什么疑问
what I'm personally what I hope
我个人就是我所希望的
especially the like all the vendors that
特别是像所有的供应商
are up here with me do is go to their
和我在一起在这里是去他们的
Java EE customers today and say look
今天的Java EE客户说说
this is a good thing for Java EE and
对于Java EE来说这是一件好事，
here's why we think it's a good thing
这就是为什么我们认为这是一件好事
and I think even but even more
而且我认为甚至更多
importantly you customers are now in a
重要的是，您的客户现在处于
position where you can engage directly
您可以直接参与的位置
with the upstream project that you're
与上游项目
going to be relying upon and we want you
将要依靠，我们希望你
to do that we want you to engage in the
为此，我们希望您参与
open source project we want you to
我们希望您的开源项目
engage in the to be defined
参与定义
specification process and we want you to
规范过程，我们希望您能够
support the Eclipse Foundation as the
支持Eclipse Foundation作为
long-term sustainable home for this for
为此的长期可持续之家
this code in this project and can I'm
这个项目中的代码，我可以
talking to our customers you know
与我们的客户交谈
speaking as an IBM websphere going
作为IBM Websphere进行演讲
obviously exactly what we're going to be
显然正是我们要成为的
doing but I think the proof of the
这样做，但我认为
pudding you know the thing that is going
布丁你知道即将发生的事情。
to make that the thing that's going to
使那将要发生的事情
convince people is when new technologies
说服人们何时使用新技术
are completed in foj and platforms that
在foj和平台中完成
have either historically supported java
具有历史上受支持的Java
re' in the past or new ones that may
是过去的或新的
find that they have a better opportunity
发现他们有更好的机会
to do so in the future actually start
将来真正开始这样做
implementing that and providing support
实施并提供支持
for those things in production which
对于生产中的那些东西
comes back to the question that Mike
回到麦克的问题
asked me yesterday which was what was my
昨天问我这是我的什么
criteria for success it is going to be
成功的标准将是
that so for me personally it is going to
所以对我个人而言
be new things being defined in open EE
是在开放式EE中定义的新事物
delivered and supported by IBM in
由IBM在
websphere and by the way in 15 minutes
Websphere并在15分钟内
time we're going to be talking about
我们要谈论的时间
Open Liberty in room 2006
2006年开放自由
please go okay last question
请最后一个问题走
probably jumping the gun in a bit but
可能会跳枪，但是
for like Eclipse workbench and the
对于像Eclipse工作台和
release train model there's the core
发布火车模型是核心
train all sub projects that wish to be a
训练所有希望成为
part of the Train released together it's
一起发行的火车的一部分是
a set clock work function you can pretty
设置时钟工作功能，您可以漂亮
much bank on the release date every year
每年发行日期都有很多钱
do you anticipate EE will follow that
您期望EE会遵循
model in terms of core definitions core
核心定义方面的模型
projects train of sub projects and use
子项目和用途的项目系列
that as a way to both continues a
作为两者的一种方式继续
stair-step model of evolution and
进化的阶梯模型
bringing related technologies in I'll
引进相关技术
first start off by saying that we were
首先说我们是
very flattered that the Java platform
Java平台非常受宠若惊
started to emulate the release train
开始模仿发布火车
process twelve years after we showed
我们展示了十二年后的过程
them that it could be done so you know
他们可以做到的，所以你知道
flattery is the your imitation is the
奉承是你的模仿是
highest form of flattery you know so but
你知道最高的奉承形式，但是
ultimately that that question is for the
最终，这个问题是针对
community to decide this is not
社区决定这不是
something the Eclipse Foundation has not
Eclipse Foundation尚未具备的功能
and will never mandate to projects that
并且永远不会强制执行那些
they must join a release train that's
他们必须参加
not that's that's never been how we roll
不是那是我们从来没有这样的方式
and it never will be how we roll that
而且永远不会是我们如何滚动
again but that said the if I could the
再次但是那说如果我可以
maturity of process that we have at the
我们拥有的过程的成熟度
Eclipse Foundation that we've
我们拥有的Eclipse Foundation
demonstrated by a book being able to hit
被一本书打中证明
a date with a major software release for
包含主要软件版本的日期
12 years in a row is I believe one of
我相信连续12年是
the reasons why the Eclipse Foundation
Eclipse Foundation的原因
was chosen as as the home so it's so
被选为家，所以
we're not going to tell anybody what to
我们不会告诉任何人
do what we are going to do is promise
做我们要做的就是承诺
that once the community decides that
一旦社区决定
they need the Eclipse Foundation to
他们需要Eclipse Foundation
support them in a particular goal we are
支持他们实现我们的特定目标
going to do our very very best to help
尽我们最大的帮助
them make that a reality I would say one
他们使我成为现实
thing that applies to that and maybe the
适用于此的东西，也许
comment is as I made earlier which is
评论就像我之前所做的是
there's a tendency in times of great
在伟大的时代有一种趋势
change for people to buckle down and
改变人们束手无策
wait and see this is the wrong time to
等待，看看这是错误的时间
buckle down and wait and see
系好安全带，拭目以待
if in a time of great change we all do
如果在一个巨大的变化时代我们都
nothing and wait for the outcome the
一无所有，等待结果
outcome is going to be nothing so now is
结果将一无是处，所以现在是
the time for us to get involved in these
我们参与这些活动的时间
conversations and if we want something
对话，如果我们想要什么
about EE to happen now is the time for
关于EE发生的时间是
us to speak up and shape it because
我们说出来并塑造它，因为
everything's malleable the piece of
一切都是可塑性的
paper is white we can write on whatever
纸是白色的，我们可以写在任何东西上
we want on it and so if you have things
我们要在上面，所以如果您有东西
that you've been wanting out of EE stand
您一直想摆脱EE立场
in line get on the list and start
排队进入清单并开始
writing them down and that's going to be
写下他们，这将是
what we do for the next couple years we
接下来的几年我们会做什么
can always change it mutate it but
可以随时更改它，但是
absolutely resist the urge to wait and
完全抵制等待的冲动
see do get involved now I've just add so
看到确实参与其中，我只是添加了
RedHat very very supportive of this but
RedHat对此非常支持，但是
we didn't get involved to help Oracle do
我们没有参与帮助Oracle做
this to get to a process that only
这只是一个过程
releases Evo j9 let's say after three
三年前发布Evo j9
years okay
好年
it's got to be released a lot quicker
它必须更快地发布
than that okay I think we're at the end
比那好吧，我认为我们快结束了
of our time please search for Eclipse
我们这个时代，请搜索Eclipse
Enterprise for Java join the mailing
Java企业版加入邮件
list give us your feedback be patient
列表给我们您的反馈要耐心
with us as we get this project moving we
与我们一起，随着我们推动这个项目的发展，
appreciate and request your support and
感谢并请求您的支持，并
thank you very much for coming
非常感谢您的光临
[Applause]
[掌声]